<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
	<channel>
		<title>John's updates</title>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Copyright (C) 2010 Goodreads Inc. All rights reserved.]]>
		</copyright>
		<link><![CDATA[http://www.goodreads.com/user/show/3983175-john-chilton]]></link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.goodreads.com/user/updates_rss/3983175" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<description><![CDATA[Recent updates from John]]></description>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 04:55:16 -0700</lastBuildDate>
		<ttl>60</ttl>
		<image>
			<title>John's updates</title>
			<link><![CDATA[http://www.goodreads.com/user/show/3983175-john-chilton]]></link>
			<width>144</width>
			<height>41</height>
			<url>http://www.goodreads.com/images/layout/goodreads_logo_144.jpg</url>
		</image>
		
		 








	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review111556947</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 04:55:16 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/111556947</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John is currently reading:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3735293-clean-code" class="bookTitle">Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship (Robert C. Martin Series)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/45372.Robert_C_Martin" class="authorName">Robert C. Martin</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=currently-reading" class="actionLinkLite">currently-reading</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review111556888</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 04:54:09 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Ejb 3 in Action']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/111556888</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John is currently reading:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/832078.Ejb_3_in_Action" class="bookTitle">Ejb 3 in Action (Paperback)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/135334.Debu_Panda" class="authorName">Debu Panda</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=currently-reading" class="actionLinkLite">currently-reading</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review110722180</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 22:06:31 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Agile Web Development with Rails: A Pragmatic Guide']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/110722180</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 4 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/45.Agile_Web_Development_with_Rails" class="bookTitle">Agile Web Development with Rails: A Pragmatic Guide (Pragmatic Programmers)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/13.Dave_Thomas" class="authorName">Dave Thomas</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=currently-reading" class="actionLinkLite">currently-reading</a>, 
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=highly-recommended" class="actionLinkLite">highly-recommended</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  I have only read seven chapters or so of this book, but I really like what I have read so far. This book isn't just about how to write applications in Rails, it is about the process of writing software. 
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review110723896</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 21:58:16 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Programming Clojure']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/110723896</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 4 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5853610-programming-clojure" class="bookTitle">Programming Clojure (Paperback)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/135290.Stuart_Halloway" class="authorName">Stuart Halloway</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=highly-recommended" class="actionLinkLite">highly-recommended</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  Context matters a lot. I am an avid functional programmer, and I read straight through this book without problem and found it to be at an entirely appropriate level. This makes me worried that this book might be too terse if this is your first book about a functional programming language. I would not call that a criticism so much as a fear, it is something to consider if you are thinking about buying this book. That aside, from my context, this is a pretty good book. This book focuses on a lot of high level ideas and syntax without getting bogged down in overly complicated examples or specific APIs. All of the writing is very clear and the examples generally seem well chosen. The high points are really nice coverage of macros and concurrency constructs. Those are two things that could have easily difficult to understand, but were not do the quality writing found in this book. I do have some criticisms of the book however. Way too much time in this book is spent covering Lancet, which seems to be an entirely dated topic just one year later. The chapter discussing sequences have some really great examples and explanations, but I am afraid I did not develop a very complete cognitive model of how everything is working, especially in terms of the ISeq interface versus specific implementations, next versus rest, etc.... One final criticism I have of the book is that the author does not discuss any of the potential drawbacks or pitfalls of using Clojure on a project. I think every book focused exclusively on one technology should have such a discussion, and I believe this especially holds for a technology as bleeding edge as Clojure. Overall this book is a pleasure to read and I would strongly recommend it.
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review110722325</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 19:34:23 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'CSS Cookbook, 2nd Edition']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/110722325</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 3 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29075.CSS_Cookbook_2nd_Edition" class="bookTitle">CSS Cookbook, 2nd Edition (Paperback)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/561.Christopher_Schmitt" class="authorName">Christopher Schmitt</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=highly-recommended" class="actionLinkLite">highly-recommended</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  This book succeeds in some places and gets fairly bogged down in others. I cannot hold that against it too much though, I read it straight through, but it probably is much better as a reference. Despite some flaws, this book has some real strengths. Unlike a lot of technical book, this book is rooted deeply in the practical. It mentions JavaScript solutions where they are useful. It has lots of links to blog posts and websites with additional information. Some books are written by people paid to write books, other books are written by practitioners who have learned from experience and have something to say. This book definitely strikes me as the latter. I think used as an actual cookbook, this book definitely deserves a spot on your bookshelf.
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review111509591</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 19:27:25 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Java EE 5 Development using GlassFish Application Server']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/111509591</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 1 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2166390.Java_EE_5_Development_using_GlassFish_Application_Server" class="bookTitle">Java EE 5 Development using GlassFish Application Server (Paperback)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/866740.David_Heffelfinger" class="authorName">David Heffelfinger</a>
    			<br/>
    			



          
    			  This book fails on many levels. I think at times it wants to be a reference book. For instance, it has long lists of vaguely described XML tags like you would find in a reference book. It covers way too much content to a suitable reference book however, it cannot dig into anything deep enough to be useful as a reference. As a tutorial on using GlasshFish in practice, I think it is probably fairly poor. It repeatedly refers the reader to the GlassFish documentation. I don't think I need to a buy a book to tell me to read the documentation. Ultimately though, frequently updated web documentation is much more appropriate for tutorials on specific software products anyways. Finally, the thing a better book could have succeeded at is being a survey of Java EE 5 technologies. This book describes all of the various technologies, but it does not spend anytime discussing the strengths and weaknesses of the technologies or describing their place in larger enterprise systems. A better book would have answered questions like - &quot;If I opt to use JSF over straight JSPs or Struts, what are the pitfalls going to be?&quot; or &quot;Its great to know how to use message queues, but what are they used for and why should I care?&quot; This is what the book should have done, this is where a good author and a good developer could really have something to say. This book is a wasted opportunity. I would still like to find a better book that covers this material. Let me know if you have found one.
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review110719511</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 19:08:51 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'ANSI Common LISP']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/110719511</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 4 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41801.ANSI_Common_LISP" class="bookTitle">ANSI Common LISP (Paperback)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/23551.Paul_Graham" class="authorName">Paul Graham</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=highly-recommended" class="actionLinkLite">highly-recommended</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  If you are going to read one book on Lisps or functional programming, it should be Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs. If you are going to read a second book, you should reread SICP. When you are ready for a third book, this is a pretty good option. This is a better book than Programming Clojure or any of the various scheme books I have read, but it is perhaps too focused on the particulars of Common LISP and not about functional programming more broadly, so there might not be as much in this book for you if you are not programming Common LISP. I could not recommend Common LISP over Scheme or Clojure, so despite the fact this is a better book I would have to recommend The Seasoned Schemer, How to Design Programs, or Programming Clojure over this book for the typical developer.
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review110721283</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 18:56:37 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Head First Design Patterns']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/110721283</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 4 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58128.Head_First_Design_Patterns" class="bookTitle">Head First Design Patterns (Head First)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/342.Elisabeth_Freeman" class="authorName">Elisabeth Freeman</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=currently-reading" class="actionLinkLite">currently-reading</a>, 
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=highly-recommended" class="actionLinkLite">highly-recommended</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  I am going to give this book a review even though I am only part of the way through, in part because I think it belongs on my highly-recommend list. The original GOF patterns book is good, is a classic, and should probably be on your bookshelf. This however is much better book on patterns for the typical developer, the content is more accessible and is more up-to-date. Moreover this book has a great attitude and is a lot of fun to read.
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review110720324</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 14:08:49 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Effective Java Programming Language Guide']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/110720324</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 4 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/105099.Effective_Java_Programming_Language_Guide" class="bookTitle">Effective Java Programming Language Guide (Paperback)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/60805.Joshua_Bloch" class="authorName">Joshua Bloch</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=highly-recommended" class="actionLinkLite">highly-recommended</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  If you program Java, you must read this book. You won't learn any new syntax, language feature, library, or framework, but you will be a much better programmer as a result of reading this book. Its the best anything on Java I have read. I don't agree with 100% of the material in this book, but Joshua Bloch has a strong, clear opinions and he argues them well. This book is so good, I think you should read it even if you aren't a Java programmer but program C#, C++, or something else along those lines. Even Ruby and Python programmers will probably get a lot out of this book.
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>

	<item>
	  <guid isPermaLink="false">Review110723326</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate>
    
  
  
  
    
    	<title>
    		<![CDATA[John added 'Grails in Action']]>
    	</title>
  	  	<link>http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/110723326</link>
  	
    	<description>
    		<![CDATA[
    			John gave 4 stars to:	<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6097506-grails-in-action" class="bookTitle">Grails in Action (Paperback)</a>
    			<span class="by">by</span>
    			<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1093634.Glen_Smith" class="authorName">Glen Smith</a>
    			<br/>
    			

	<span class="userReview">bookshelves: </span>
	
		<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/3983175-john-chilton?shelf=highly-recommended" class="actionLinkLite">highly-recommended</a>
	
	<br/>



          
    			  Surprisingly good. This book did a good job explaining grails and even more important making be excited to program in it. I highly recommend this book.
    			
    		]]>
    	</description>
  	
    

  </item>



	</channel>
</rss>
